const e="apes_ch5",o="Chapter 5",i=[{number:1,question:"________ occurs when one organism feeds on the body of, or the energy used by, another organism, usually by living on or in it.",choices:["Parasitism","Commensalism","Mutualism","Predation"],correct:0},{number:2,question:"Which of the following illustrates a predator-prey relationship?",choices:["honeybee and flower","lion and hyena","cow and grass","squirrel and rabbit"],correct:2},{number:3,question:"Some prey are able to avoid predation by mimicry. An example of mimicry is when a",choices:["caterpillar looks like a twig.","startled caterpillar inflates structures that pop out to look like horns.","non-poisonous butterfly looks like a poisonous butterfly.","poison arrow frog has bright colors."],correct:2},{number:4,question:"The relationship formed between organisms that affect each other's evolution is called",choices:["secondary succession.","coevolution.","resource partitioning.","commensalism."],correct:1},{number:5,question:"This interaction benefits one organism, but neither helps nor harms a second organism.",choices:["mutualism","parasitism","predation","commensalism"],correct:3},{number:6,question:"One way that species reduce competition for the same resources is by",choices:["reducing niche overlap through resource partitioning.","exceeding the carrying capacity to drive out competition.","stimulating mutations that make them more fit.","increasing niche overlap to drive out competing species."],correct:0},{number:7,question:"Which of the following is not within the study of population dynamics?",choices:["density of organisms","distribution","age structure","resource availability"],correct:3},{number:8,question:"Organismal populations may grow, shrink, or remain stable over time. Population change",choices:["cannot yet be mathematically modeled.","is dependent only on births and deaths.","may be influenced by emigration and immigration.","is independent of the population's age structure."],correct:2},{number:9,question:"Which of the following is false?",choices:["There are always limits to population growth in nature.","Individuals in populations with high intrinsic rate of growth typically reproduce early, have short generation times, can reproduce many times, and have many offspring at each reproduction.","Species moved to regions where they are not native will still have the same environmental resistance pressures as native species.","The growth rate of a population decreases as it nears its carrying capacity."],correct:2},{number:10,question:"Which of the following is true? Exponential growth",choices:["slows down when approaching a species' carrying capacity.","is maintained as long as environmental resistance factors are high.",'is represented by a "J-shaped" curve when plotting population numbers over time.',"is slow at the start, fast in the middle, and slow at the end."],correct:2},{number:11,question:"Species with a capacity for a high rate of increase of ten produce many small offspring and give them little or no parental care. Such species are called ________ species.",choices:["predator","commensal","K-selected","r-selected"],correct:3},{number:12,question:"A volcanic eruption destroyed most of the population of a species of monkey living in the area. The few that survived will now reproduce and rebuild the population, however the resulting population will have a reduced genetic diversity. This scenario describes",choices:["demographic bottleneck.","founder effect.","genetic drift.","inbreeding."],correct:0},{number:13,question:"Examples of density-dependent population limiting factors include all of the following except",choices:["parasitism.","predation.","fire.","disease."],correct:2},{number:14,question:"Skunks have few predators, yet their populations change relatively little from one year to the next. Such a species demonstrates ________ pattern of variation in its population size.",choices:["irruptive","irregular","stable","cyclic"],correct:2},{number:15,question:"Population controls are factors that limit population size for a given environment. Which of the following would be considered a human population control?",choices:["HIV leading to AIDS","war","all of the choices","famine"],correct:2},{number:16,question:"The following is an example of primary succession.",choices:["An old parking lot eventually becomes a temperate forest.","Abandoned farmland eventually becomes a forest.","An old Iowa farm becomes a prairie.","An abandoned lot eventually is replaced by weeds and shrubs."],correct:0},{number:17,question:"The following is an example of secondary succession.",choices:["A volcanic island eventually becomes a lush tropical rainforest.","A retreating glacier leaves behind land that becomes arctic tundra.","An old parking lot eventually becomes a temperate forest.","Abandoned farmland eventually becomes a forest."],correct:3},{number:19,question:"The ability of a living system to be restored through secondary succession after a moderate disturbance is called",choices:["tipping point.","persistence.","inertia.","resilience."],correct:3}],t={id:e,displayName:o,questions:i};export{t as default,o as displayName,e as id,i as questions};
